Bring out Elizabeth Selwyn.
Bring out the witch!
Bring her out.
Sssss...
Witch!
Burn her!
Burn her! Burn her!
Burn the witch!
Jethrow, Jethrow,
Jethrow!
Jethrow Keane,
hast thou consorted with
the witch Elizabeth Selwyn?
No.
Burn the witch!
Please no!
No, no...
No!
No, no, no, no...
Help her, oh Lucifer, help her!
Elizabeth Selwyn...
on this third day of March,
in the year of our Lord 1692.
We the people
of Whitewood, Massachusetts,
condemn thee as a witch.
May the flames cleanse thy soul
of its evil,
of its lust for blood!
That made thee bring about
the death of Abigail Adams.
Help her, oh Lucifer, help her!
I have made my pact
with thee, oh Lucifer.
Hear me, hear me.
I will do thy bidding
for all eternity.
For all eternity shall I
practice the ritual
of Black Mass.
For all eternity
shall I sacrifice unto thee.
And I give thee my soul.
Take me into thy service.
Oh, Lucifer,
listen to thy servant.
Grant her this pact
for all eternity and I with her.
And if we fail thee but once,
you may do with our souls
what you will.
Make this city an example
of thy vengeance.
Curse it,
Curse it for all eternity.
- A curse.
- And let me
be the instrument of thy curse.
Hear me, oh Lucifer, hear me!
- She's making a curse.
- Curse?
- A Curse?
- Burn her!
Burn witch! Burn witch, Burn!
Burn! Burn! Burn! Burn!
Burn witch!
Burn witch, Burn!
Burn witch! Burn witch!
Burn, witch, burn, witch,
burn, burn, burn.
So shouted the people
of Whitewood
when they burned
Elizabeth Selwyn in 1692.
Though, as I've said,
little is known today
of the actual practice
of witchcraft
in 17th century New England,
superstition, fear and jealousy
drove the Puritans to accuse
their friends and relatives
of consorting with the devil.
Parading around huge bonfires
repeating vindictive chants
they consigned the poor
creatures to the flames.
The tortured souls
cried out in agony
as the flames mounted
higher and higher!
"Burn, witch! Burn, witch!
Burn! Burn!! Burn!"
- Dig that crazy beat.
- Shh!
That will be all for today.
Tomorrow will be
my concluding lecture
on the history of witchcraft
in 17th century New England.
I shall bring along
some illustrations
which I'm sure
will interest you all.
I'll bring the matches.
Maitland!
Since you chose
to attend these lectures,
I had hoped
that it was in the spirit
of scientific curiosity
about the subject.
That will be all.
Bill, how could you?
He takes it all so darn serious.
He's got you all hypnotized.
Oh, Miss Barlow.
Yes, Professor.
Can I see you
for a moment, please?
What about our date?
I'll meet you - - Look, um...
I'll wait for you outside, huh.
Yes, Professor?
Rather a difficult
young man there.
I fear that you are more
of an attraction to him
than my poor efforts.
However,
I've been reading through
your papers, Miss Barlow.
They show a very sound
appreciation of the subject.
I want to go to New England
to do my senior paper.
Uh huh, you're really
quite good, you know.
Well, I'm not quite satisfied...
I feel I need
some first hand research.
I want to get the atmosphere.
Find out how widespread
witchcraft really was,
what the witches
were really like.
That might take
a little time, you know.
Well, I have the time.
My brother and I were
going to spend our vacation
with our cousins.
What I'd really like to do,
is to get a room
in the smallest, oldest town
in New England I can find.
Check through all
the Town Hall records,
re-check the libraries,
talk to the Puritan descendants,
make a really thorough
investigation.
Your brother is Professor
of Science, Miss Barlow,
I hardly think he'd
be very interested
in the history of witchcraft.
Then, I'd go alone.
You don't think he'd object
to that?
You leave Richard to me.
He's picking me up here
for lunch.
Hello, Bill.
- Professor Barlow.
- Nan here?
Yeah, she's in there with him.
Well, I don't like her
getting mixed up
in this witchcraft business.
Why not? It's only part
of a history course.
- Professor Barlow?
- Yeah?
Before you go in there, could,
could I have a word with you?
Why sure.
- Well, it's about Nan and me.
- Oh.
If you're really serious
about this,
I happen to know of a town
in New England.
As a matter of fact, it's the
identical place where the events
occurred I mentioned
in today's lecture, Whitewood.
It's, uh, quite a small place,
it's a little bit off
the beaten track,
so maybe these directions
will help you.
Thank you.
I think you might very well find
what you are looking for there.
I happen to know the woman
who owns the inn in Whitewood.
Her name is Newless,
Mrs. Newless,
so you just tell her I sent you.
Ravens Inn, Whitewood.
What's Whitewood?
Now Dick,
don't be too upset but, uh,
I'm gonna change my plans
for vacation.
Change your plans?
Yes
I'm going to a place called
Whitewood for a week or so
to do some research.
Oh, are you?
And what about cousin Sue?
Why she's expecting you
for her birthday party
on the 17th,
she'll never forgive you.
I can still easily make it
by then,
this is important.
My term paper's got to be good,
it could mean a scholarship.
Nan, I've made all the
arrangements.
Come on, Dick, you'll have
a good time without me.
My mind's made up,
I'm going to Whitewood.
But surely any good encyclopedia
will give you all the nonsense
you want to know
about witchcraft.
Witchcraft
is not nonsense, Barlow!
I'm sorry, Driscoll, witchcraft,
black magic, sorcery...
to me it's nothing
but fairy tale, mumbo-jumbo.
I'm a scientist Driscoll,
I believe what I can see
what I can feel and touch.
The basis of fairy tales
is reality,
the basis of reality
is fairy tales.
As a scientist, you should be
familiar with that quotation.
Ya, well I don't believe
that somebody in Chicago,
can die of a heart-attack
because
some woman in New Orleans
sticks a pin in a wax doll.
Maybe you don't!
But practitioners of voodoo
claim otherwise.
Dick, you're just
being difficult.
No!
When I look into a
microscope, Driscoll,
I see bacteria swimming,
fighting, existing, that's real.
These witches that were
persecuted and burned
in the 17th century were real
too, but they weren't witches.
They were pitiful human beings.
Victims of hysteria.
There are many eminent scholars
who have documentary proof
of the actual
practice of witchcraft.
Yeah, but how effective
was this practice?
Did any of these
eminent scholars
ever meet a real
practicing witch?
Did you ever
meet a witch, Driscoll?
Perhaps.
Ah, come on,
you're a historian.
No witch ever survived
the burning at the stake
for all their pacts
with the devil.
In sixteen hundred and
ninety two,
Elizabeth Selwyn went
to the stake.
She was buried in a church yard
in New England.
And yet three years later,
Yeah?
Three years later, a new wave
of blood sacrifices
broke out in the village
that had condemned her.
The daughters of the elders
who had condemned her
were themselves found murdered
with every last drop of blood
drained from their bodies.
And afterwords,
people came forward to testify
that they had actually seen
Elizabeth Selwyn.
Oh, stop. This would be more
effective at midnight
with howling winds
and crashing thunder
and even then
it wouldn't frighten anyone.
Dick!
I'm sorry, Professor Driscoll.
That's alright, Miss Barlow.
He won't be the first person
to have scoffed at the subject.
Honey, when you get to um...
where is it?
Whitewood. Ah, yes, Whitewood.
Well, send me a picture postcard
of a witch,
if possible, autographed.
Now, uh,
let's have some lunch, huh?
I'm sorry, I have a date.
Nan, darling, I still don't see
why you have to go off
to this Whitewood place. Now...
I thought we were going
to have some time together
during this vacation.
You know I want to be with you,
it's just this is important...
Look, what the heck can you find
that hasn't been found before?
I don't know.
It's just that maybe,
hidden in some attic, or
buried in some old antique shop
there's something that might
give a whole new outlook
to the subject.
Oh what new outlook
can there be?
You're a science student, honey,
you know how important
research is.
But this isn't
about anything real.
This is just superstitious
people burning silly old women.
But suppose the women
weren't silly?
Suppose they really
had a pact with the devil?
A pact that could have
supernatural power.
Oh, come on, what kind of power?
I don't know.
Well, look, it's no use, Bill.
We've both tried our hardest
to talk her out of going.
Do you really think she will
find anything worthwhile?
Well, I think we have to respect
her desire to find something new
even if we... even if we don't
agree with the subject.
Agree with it?
I've never heard
so much nonsense
as that guy Driscoll talks,
in all my life!
Well, here I am, all packed.
Oh, I suppose nothing I can say
will stop you from going, huh?
Yeah, well, I'll uh,
I'll put this in the car.
I still hoped you'd
change your mind, Nan.
Don't worry darling.
I'll be back as quick
as I can, and I'll write.
Well, don't forget me
all together, huh?
I won't.
Give Sue my love and
don't forget we have a date
at her party.
Good-bye, darling.
Um, excuse me, can you help me?
I seem to be lost.
Sure, if I can.
I'm looking for the Wamport Road.
Wamport Road? Hardly anyone
uses that any more.
Well, my friend
gave me the directions, uh..
Take Road 28-A,
Turn on to the Wamport Road,
bare left at the fork
through to Whitewood.
Whitewood!?
Am I that far away?
No ma'am, not far...
Not many God fearing folks
visit Whitewood nowadays.
If I were you I'd - Well if...
if you'll excuse me,
I'm in a hurry.
Which way is it?
Well, follow this road
about 2 miles,
you come to a fork
there'll be a sign, Wamport Road.
Turn left, keep straight,
there be Whitewood.
Thank you very much.
Does that sign say Wamport Road?
Wamport Road? Yes.
Oh good, I was afraid
I missed it.
Is it, uh, Whitewood you seek?
Yes.
I too.
Uh, would I be imposing if-
No, of course not, get in.
Thank you.
You'd think the highway
commission would do something
about these roads.
Watch out,
here comes another bump.
What is your mission
in Whitewood?
Mission?
Well, I'm going there
to do some research
on witchcraft.
Professor Driscoll gave us
some very interesting lectures
on the subject and
I'm going there to get
some original source material.
Do you know Whitewood?
I've known it for many years.
Do you go there often?
Fairly often.
Oh, then you must know
the Raven's Inn?
I shall be resting there.
Oh, so shall I.
Oh, my name is Nan Barlow.
My name is Jethrow Keane.
Pleased to meet you.
It's just like a picture
out of a history book.
I feel as though I were
in the seventeenth century.
Why hasn't Whitewood
been written about?
It's off the beaten path.
Few tourists come here.
For Whitewood,
time stands still.
Look at that church,
must have been beautiful.
What a shame
they let it get so run down.
Straight on?
Yes. Follow the road around.
Ah, there it is!
What a lovely old building.
Seventeenth century at least.
How picturesque can you get?
Right by the graveyard.
Yes, it has not been used
for more than two hundred years.
Any witches buried there?
There are indeed...
all in a section
of unconsecrated ground.
Spooky isn't it?
Well, keep your fingers crossed
for me, Mr. Keane.
I hope Mrs. Newless
has that room.
Oh, I didn't hear you come in.
Are you Mrs. Newless?
No.
Oh,
I'm Nan Barlow, I was told
I might find a room here.
I was recommended by a friend
of mine, Professor Driscoll,
perhaps you know him?
That will be all, Lottie.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
Unfortunately,
Lottie can not talk.
I've often told her
not to answer the bell.
Oh, poor thing.
Then you're Mrs. Newless?
Wm, may I help you?
Yes, I'd like to have
a room here for two weeks.
The hotel is quite full.
Oh, the guests are never
about at this time of the day.
Well, I'm a student
of Professor Driscoll's.
He told me if I mentioned
his name, I'd have no trouble.
Well, there is a room
I could let you have,
it's just off the lobby.
Oh, thank you.
Oh, Mrs. Newless,
that plaque,
is it true that Elizabeth Selwyn
was really burned here
for being a witch?
She was.
And do you believe
she was a witch?
Come along.
I'll show you to your room.
I hope you will be comfortable.
Yes, it is a nice room.
The previous occupants have
always found it most agreeable.
Well,
if there's anything
you should need
just ring the bell for me
at the desk.
Thank you.
Oh!
It's been so many months,
I've counted the days
to this holiday.
So have the others.
It wasn't easy for some
of my guests to get here.
Many had to travel
vast distances.
I was lucky, the last few miles
were enchanting.
Miss Barlow
is very good company.
You must be tired, Jethrow,
your room is ready.
And the festivities?
I am prepared.
Oh, Mrs. Newless.
I thought I'd have
a short look around town,
I won't be gone long.
I think you'll find
the church interesting,
unfortunately it no longer
has a congregation.
He will be pleased.
I'm told this was once
a house of worship.
It is still a house of worship.
I am the reverend
of this church
as long as the breath of life
is within me,
this house shall remain
God's house.
Must have been
a beautiful building.
To me, it is still beautiful.
I'm sorry.
What a shame
the people have let it fall
into such a state.
Strangers rarely come
to Whitewood.
Who are you?
I'm Nan Barlow,
I'm staying at the Raven's Inn.
Why have you come to Whitewood?
Well...
because I'm interested
in witchcraft.
Young woman, leave Whitewood.
Leave Whitewood tonight.
For 300 years,
the devil has hovered
over this city,
made it his own.
The people in it, are his.
Evil has triumphed
over good, here.
Look at my church,
I have no parish.
No one worships here.
His is the power.
What power?
Leave Whitewood.
Leave Whitewood tonight!
I beg of you!
What power?
Leave before it is too late!
- Good evening.
Please excuse the mess,
we haven't been open long.
You have some
very interesting things here.
Yes, they, they belonged
to my grandmother.
When she died, I came back
to sort things out.
Oh, I'm sorry,
then you don't live here?
No, my family have lived here
for generations
but I've just been back
a few weeks.
Would you like
to have a look around?
Thank you.
Oh, I didn't mean
to frighten you when I came in.
It's just that all the people
I've met here
have acted like I'm a person
from another world.
They don't see
many strangers here.
And I had the most...
well unusual experience
with the reverend.
He barred my way
from the church.
And he talked to me
about a curse.
And he warned me
to leave Whitewood.
Can you explain that?
No, I can't.
Does he often act that way?
He's my grandfather.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Oh, it's alright, it's happened
before with strangers.
With the lack of parishioners
and loss of his sight,
has made him bitter
and suspicious.
I'm afraid what with him
and the town,
I, I was very scared.
When I saw your lights,
I made a dash for them.
I'm glad you did.
Urn, do you have any books
or pamphlets on witchcraft?
You do don't you,
a friend of mine...
Well, we, we have
a collection gathering dust
but why on earth would you
be interested in...
Oh, I'm sorry, it's really
none of my business.
No, that's alright,
I'm studying it in college
and I've come here
to write my term paper.
Well, just wait,
I'll see what I can find.
That's Elizabeth Selwyn, burned
as a witch, March 3rd, 1692.
Yes, I know, I saw the plaque
in the lobby of the hotel.
You're staying
at the Raven's Inn?
Yes, it was recommended to me
by a friend, Professor Driscoll.
Alan Driscoll?
Yes, do you know him?
No, but my grandfather
speaks of him.
His family come from here.
Oh, I didn't know that.
Here, I think this will do
for a start.
What a lovely locket,
may I see it?
I believe it's quite old.
Oh, it is!
You're very lucky.
I'm even more lucky
to have found this,
"A Treatise On Devil Worship
In New England."
This must be a very rare book.
I'm afraid
I couldn't afford to buy it.
You can borrow it, if you like.
Oh, could I?!
That would be wonderful!
I promise I'll bring it back
in a few days.
You're very welcome, Miss, uh?
Barlow. Nan Barlow.
Nan Barlow.
Thank you very much,
good night.
Good night.
Mrs. Newless!
Yes, Miss Barlow.
I, I heard some strange noises
in my room.
Oh, possibly the water in the
pipes, this is a very old inn.
No, it seemed to be coming
from the cellar underneath.
I hardly think so, Ms. Barlow.
The cellars do not extend
beneath your room.
Then why is there a trap door
in the floor?
The ground was filled in
many years ago
to strengthen the foundations
of the building.
But I'm sure I...
Well, if you insist,
I will come and see.
I don't hear anything.
Well, just a few minutes ago...
Never mind, I'm sorry.
You're welcome.
But you can see for yourself
there is no ring
in the trap door
because there is no reason
to lift it.
There is nothing underneath
but earth.
Come in.
Oh, hello, Lottie, come in.
Oh, I don't need
any more towels.
I haven't used mine.
They're quite clean.
Lottie!
I've told you before
not to bother the guests.
Miss Barlow, I thought you might
care to join the others.
I will as soon as
I finish my notes.
I'll put some clothes on
and join them.
"A Treatise On Devil Worship
In New England."
Well, do you find this
interesting?
Why it's fascinating.
The things I've learnt,
I bet you don't know
the half of it.
And you live right here
on a spot where the witches
were actually burnt.
Listen to this.
On Candlemas Eve, February 1st,
in the year
sixteen-hundred and ninety two,
a coven of witches,
a coven, that's 13,
some men some women
whose power came from the Devil
gathered beneath the Raven's Inn
to perform a Black Mass
in the honor of Lucifer.
The witch, Elizabeth Selwyn,
later to be burnt at the stake,
marked a young girl
for sacrifice,
by obtaining an object of value
belonging to her,
with which to call her.
And leaving in its place
a dead bird
and a sprig of Woodbine.
The witches sacrificed her
on the altar
and drank her blood
at the hour of 13.
What's the hour of 13?
Well personally, I have never
heard a clock strike
more than 12.
Now,
how about joining the dancing?
In a little while, I promise.
Oh, by the way,
I seem to have misplaced
my locket.
I remember having it in my room
and now it's disappeared.
Oh, I'm sorry, I,
I'll ask Lottie.
Well, I, I'm not saying
it was stolen, its just,
I remember having it
on the dresser and
now its gone.
I would appreciate it.
Of course.
I'll look into it immediately.
Lottie,
I have warned you too often
about annoying our guests.
If you disobey me again,
I shall turn you out.
And if I turn you out,
there will be no place
for you anywhere.
You do understand,
Lottie, don't you?
Ah, Miss Barlow.
I'm afraid Lottie
is no where to be found.
But I will inquire
about your locket
first thing in the morning.
Oh, thank you.
Where is everybody?
Most of the other guests
have gone to services.
Services,
on the 1st of February?
Candlemas Eve.
The night when the witches
mock the rituals of the church.
Are you alright, Miss Barlow?
Yes, quite, thank you.
Good night.
Good night, Miss Barlow.
Gasp!
Mrs. Newless!
Mrs. Newless! Mrs. Newless!
- Quiet!
Help!
No!
Ah! No! Let go of me!
Help! No!
Let me go! Ahh, no!
Ahh, take your hands off of me!
Let me go!
No! No, no, let go of me!
No!
- Three,
Four
Five.
Six, - Wait!
Seven - Eight.
No! No Mrs. Newless, no!
No, no, no!
I am Elizabeth Selwyn.
- Eleven...
- Noooo!
Let go of me, let go...
Yeah!!!
Happy Birthday to you,
Happy Birthday to you.
Happy Birthday, dear Suzie,
Happy Birthday to you!
Yeah!
Urn, yummy-
Delicious.
Dick, have you got any idea
what's happened to Nan?
I'm sure she'll show up.
She, she's probably met
a good looking he-witch
and is bringing him
along to the party,
only their broomstick
blew a gasket.
It's not like Nan to be late
for anything.
Aren't you a bit worried
about her?
Oh, she'll be here,
I'm sure she'll make it.
That's probably her now.
Well, you answer the door and
I'm going to put a record on
- for some dancing.
- Alright.
- Hi, Dick.
- Bill.
Well, what's the matter, you
were expecting somebody else?
Why, yes, Nan.
Look, come in, come in.
Well, Nan, isn't she here yet?
We made a date to meet here
before she left for Whitewood.
Well, she probably got held up.
Look, look, give me your coat,
huh.
Aw, Nan was never late
for anything in her life.
Relax, take it easy.
Join the party, she'll be here.
Dick.
Dick, I haven't had a letter
from Nan in over 2 weeks now.
She's probably been too busy
working on her paper.
No, no, there's something wrong,
I know it.
Look, will you do something
for me?
Uh huh.
Ring up Whitewood, will ya?
Ask 'em, ask 'em if she's left.
You serious?
Yes, I am.
OK.
Hello, long distance,
I'd like to speak
with a Miss Nan Barlow
at the Raven's Inn, Whitewood.
No, I, uh, I don't know
the phone number.
What, didn't she give you the
phone number?
Why no, but, uh,
that's my sister.
They say there's no such place
as the Raven's Inn.
But that's crazy,
she's staying there.
Get me the police!
She left in such a hurry,
she must have forgotten
to return it to you,
Miss Russell.
She seemed such a nice girl too.
Wouldn't have thought
she was the sort
to forget to return a book.
We can not always judge by our
first impressions, can we?
I'm not usually wrong about
the people I lend my books to.
Well, perhaps you'll be
more careful in the future.
Thank you
for letting me have it.
Remember me
to your grandfather.
Lottie!
Get out of the way,
you clumsy creature.
Can I help you?
Yes, we're from
the Sheriff's Office.
We had a call this evening.
A missing persons report on some
college kid named Nan Barlow.
The party calling said that
her last known whereabouts
was the Raven's Inn.
Nan Barlow, that's strange.
Yes, I met her.
When did you last see her?
About two weeks ago.
She came to my shop
and borrowed this book,
it's quite valuable and
so not hearing from her,
I decided to come and get it.
Mrs. Newless had it.
- May I?
- Yes.
"A Treatise On Devil Worship"?
I must put this in the report.
Peculiar things some of these
college kids do nowadays.
Well, thanks for your help.
Come on Charlie.
Hello.
Ya.
It's the police.
OK, thanks.
Thank you.
Well?
The police sent a car
out to the Raven's Inn.
Nan checked out two weeks ago.
I don't get it.
Well, neither do I.
Look, these are Nan's
books and papers,
go through them, see if you can
find anything
which might give us a lead.
I'm going to pay a visit
to a colleague of mine.
Oh, lord of light,
accept this sacrifice.
- Why, Barlow.
- May I come in?
Yes, of course, please do.
Can I take your coat?
I tried to phone you last night,
but I guess you weren't in.
No, uh, no, I wasn't.
Would you care to go
into the study?
- Sit yourself down.
- Thanks.
Would you take a drink?
Rye and soda.
- Ice?
- Please.
Now what's on your mind?
Nan's missing
and she has been since the day
after she arrived at Whitewood.
Really, you quite sure?
That's what the police said.
What are they doing about it?
Carry out a routine check, I,
I don't suppose they can do
much more until they've got
something definite to go on.
I would have thought
there was a very great deal
- more they could do.
- What?
As far as they're concerned, she
disappeared 2 weeks ago
and no one in the village seems
to know anything about it.
What have you come see me for?
I thought you might
have some ideas.
Why did you send her
to Whitewood?
Because it was the best place
for her research...
And you suggested she stay
at the Raven's Inn.
Sure,
it's the only inn there is.
With an unlisted phone number?
The inn has it's own clientele,
Barlow,
it doesn't need to advertise.
How do you know it so well?
Because I was born
in Whitewood.
I see. And you'd have every
reason to believe
she'd be safe in going there.
I have no reason to suppose
that she wouldn't be.
Nan struck me as
being perfectly capable
of taking care of herself.
I grant you that, but why hasn't
she come back or let us know?
Look, Barlow,
I can understand your anxiety
but I'm quite sure there's
nothing for you to worry about,
nothing at all. She's probably
got absorbed in subjects
and gone off someplace.
I wish that all my class
had her application.
Ya, well I'm going to find out
where this application led her.
I'm going to retrace
every step Nan took.
I'm either going to find Nan
or know what happened to her.
I can't stop you from going.
No.
You're not afraid? Afraid, why?
Well, if anything did happen to
your sister and somebody else
went along to try
and find out about it.
Same thing might happen to them?
Possible.
You seem to think something
happened to my sister then?
No, I just think you're jumping
to conclusions, Barlow.
Maybe, but I shall find her.
- Professor Driscoll?
- Yes.
I don't like to disturb you,
but may I see you?
Well, of course, please come in.
Good luck in Whitewood. Thanks.
I'm sorry, but did you say
he was going to Whitewood?
Yes, he is.
Silly to be surprised but, uh,
I've just come from Whitewood.
Really?
Quite a coincidence,
My own family happens
to come from Whitewood.
As a matter of fact,
I was born there. - Yes, I know.
- Please sit down.
- Thank you.
Do you care for a drink?
No, thank you.
I think you know my grandfather,
the Reverend Russell.
Russell?
Why, yes, of course I do.
How long have you
been living in Whitewood?
Since my grandmother died
a few weeks ago.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Well now, how can I help you?
I've come about a pupil of yours
Barlow, Nan Barlow.
Yes.
She came to Whitewood
two weeks ago.
I met her and liked her
and she told me
that she was a student
in one of your classes,
that you recommended that
she stay at the Raven's Inn.
That's quite right, I did.
Well, that's what I've come
to see you about.
On the day after she arrived,
she disappeared.
Oh?
Later the police
came asking questions,
Her family were worried.
I thought you might
have their address.
And why do you want
her family's address?
Because I have something
of hers I want to return.
Well, you just leave it with me
and I'll make sure
they get it safely.
Well, I don't want
to trouble you,
if you'd just give me
their address.
As you wish.
Her address is Dorchester St.,
2-2-5.
She lives with her brother.
As a matter of fact.
He's a colleague of mine,
you just met him.
He was leaving
when you arrived.
Now, if you'll excuse me,
I've got a lot of work to do,
I'm rather a busy man
at the moment.
Of course,
thank you for your help.
Not at all, I hope
it achieves something.
Well, you will remember me
to your grandfather, won't you?
Yes, of course. Good-bye.
Good-bye Ms. Russell.
Yeah,
that's Nan's locket alright.
As far as I know, it's unique.
I gave it to her,
where did you get it?
The servant at the inn gave
it to me. It was strange.
I don't think she wanted Mrs.
Newless to know I had it.
Mrs. Newless? She runs the inn.
Well, why did you come here,
Miss, Miss Russell?
I found this.
It's Professor Driscoll's
note paper.
I found it in the pages
of a book I lent your sister
on her first evening
in Whitewood.
When she didn't return it,
I went to the hotel.
What was the book?
An old book.
A book about witchcraft.
Do you believe in it,
Miss Russell?
I don't know.
Sometimes I almost think
I live with it.
Live with it?
It's an obsession
of my grandfather's.
Up to now, I didn't take him
very seriously. He's an old man,
but now I'm beginning to wonder
if what he says isn't true.
What does he say?
That there is something evil
about the village.
That on certain nights, the
inhabitants leave the streets,
close their doors and stay
behind them.
That on these nights,
the dead come to life.
Nights like Candlemas Eve?
What do you know
about Candlemas Eve?
It's in one of Nan's books.
I don't believe it!
Things like this
don't happen today.
In Whitewood, I wonder.
I'm going to Whitewood tomorrow,
after classes,
I could give you a lift.
Thank you, but I must get back,
I can't leave my grandfather
alone, he's blind.
May I come and see you
when I arrive?
I'd, uh, I'd like to have
a talk With him.
Please do, it's the house
next to the church.
- Good-bye.
I'll see you to the door.
Would you be going to Whitewood?
Yes.
Would you take me
along with you?
It's a dark night for walking.
You're the Reverend Russell's
granddaughter, aren't you?
Yes, how did you know?
I know a great deal
about Whitewood.
Have you ever been there?
Now and then.
I've never seen you.
To see me
is a special privilege
reserved for a chosen few.
What does that mean?
We'll soon be at Whitewood now.
This is as far as I go,
you will...
She's pretty too.
Yes, she is. Very pretty.
A living decedent
of those who were cursed.
That somehow seems
to make it better.
- Another day.
- And tomorrow.
The Witches Sabbath.
Which way to Wamport Road?
Straight ahead. Fork in the
road, you see a sign,
Turn left...
You headin' for Whitewood?
I am.
Many people head this way?
Not many.
Is this the only way in and out
of the town?
In this direction, yup.
You wouldn't remember
by any chance,
a pretty girl in a convertible
about a month ago?
The Barlow girl,
read about her in the papers,
never seen her again.
Told the police.
Thanks.
Owner, could you tell me the way
to Whitewood, please?
Another one! Straight ahead,
fork in the road, you see a sign.
Wamport Road.
Turn left, takes you right in.
Why thanks.
Let me warn you young fellow,
they don't like strangers
in Whitewood.
Okay, fine, thanks very much.
- Good evening.
I'd like a room, please.
The inn is closing.
I'll only be here a few days.
But the inn is closing.
- When?
- In two days.
Well, if you don't mind,
I'd like to stay until then.
If you insist.
Could I, could I have the, uh,
same room, my, my sister had?
It's still available, isn't it?
Yes, it's available.
Mrs. Newless you told the police
that my sister checked out.
You are mistaken, Mr. Barlow.
I told them that on the
morning of February 2nd,
I went to her room and found it
empty, her bed not slept in,
her luggage and car gone,
and her bill unpaid.
Well, you can put the charges
on mine.
When was the last time
you saw her?
On the evening of February 1st.
It was shortly before midnight,
she'd been in the lobby here
dancing with some
of the guests.
She seemed
to be enjoying herself.
Did any particular guest pay a,
a special attention to her?
Not that I noticed.
Your sister kept very much
to herself.
Do you know why
she came to Whitewood?
It is not my habit to inquire
into people's private business.
Would the fact that she was,
she was investigating witchcraft
had antagonized
anyone in the village?
Hardly, there have been
other students here you know.
Besides, your sister
was a very agreeable
and likable young woman.
Have you any idea of where
she might have gone?
None.
Thank you.
Now, may I see the room?
As you wish. It is this way.
If you should need anything
and I am not at the desk,
you have only to ring the bell.
Thank you.
Hello. I'm so glad you've come.
I saw your car
outside the Raven's Inn earlier
I wondered what
had happened to you.
I've been talking
with Mrs. Newless
and then I took a walk
around the village.
Find out anything?
Everyone here seems
to be afraid of something.
Then you don't think
it's just my imagination?
I don't know.
Whose to say where imagination
ends and truth begins.
It's nothing tangible. It's
just they way they look at you.
I felt it too.
May I see the book
that Nan borrowed?
Yes, I put a marker
between the pages
where she must have
stopped reading.
Just sit down and I'll tell
my grandfather you're here.
Thank you.
I warned you, Lottie.
Grandfather, this is Mr. Barlow.
How do you do, Sir?
God be with you.
Shall we sit where we'll be
more comfortable?
Here's your chair, Grandfather.
You must be tired.
I am, really tired.
I have little strength left
these days for the fight.
Won't you sit down,
I'll make some coffee.
The fight against what,
Mr. Russell?
Against the evil
that besets this village.
The people are creatures
of the devil.
They know no other god.
Do you mean they worship Satan
here... today?
Satanism was never stronger
than at the present time.
For 200 hundred years,
the people of Whitewood
have carried out rituals
that mock the Church's teaching.
I find it very hard to believe,
Sir. I...
Do not doubt, my son.
It is real enough.
For years I struggled
against the witches.
Their master
took away my sight.
It seems incredible.
I have tried to convince others.
They, too,
found it unbelievable.
But I know these people
have a pact with the devil.
To worship him
and do his works.
In return,
he gives them eternal life.
- Eternal life?
- Aye.
And to seal this bargain, they
must sacrifice a young girl
on two nights of the year.
When are these nights, Sir?
Candlemas Eve
and the Witches' Sabbath.
Candlemas Eve,
that's February the first.
And when is the Witches Sabbath?
Tonight.
Now you know why
I came to see you.
I had no idea it was so late.
May I, may I have a rain-check
on the coffee?
I'd like to have a few words
with Mrs. Newless again.
Of course.
Good night, Sir.
Good night.
I'll see you to the door.
God be with us.
Oh, Miss Russell,
do you think that
Nan's disappearance
is connected in some way
with these, uh,
witch's ceremonies?
Yes.
I'd, uh, I'd like to come back
later, if I may?
Please do. And my name is Pat.
Mine's Richard.
I think I feel better now
you're here.
Well, I'm, I'm going to stay
until I find out
what's happened to Nan.
Take care.
Now drink your coffee
before it gets cold.
You must not see
that young man again tonight.
Why not?
The devil comes
in many disguises.
I'll get you a spoon.
Grandfather, there's a bird
in the drawer.
It's got an arrow through it.
Go and look on the front door!
It's a sprig of Woodbine.
Shut the door!
Shut the door quickly!
Grandfather, what does it mean?
Now listen, my darling.
This is their sign,
the witches' sign.
What can we do?
We must leave here.
Leave here immediately!
I'll start the car.
Something's wrong.
They've wrecked the car.
Barlow, phone Barlow!
Hello, hello?
Hello, I want the Raven's Inn.
Yes, Mrs. Newless.
Mr. Barlow?
- Is that for me?
- Yes.
Hello.
Dick, Dick,
I'm in terrible danger!
We've got to leave Whitewood
at once!
Danger? But from what?
We've got to leave...
- Pat! Patricia!
- Please help me!
Pat!
Patricia!
Mr. Russell, are you there?
Where is she?
What's happened, Mr. Russell?
The witches!
The witches have Patricia!
Destroy them!
Mr. Russell, how?
The shadow of the cross.
Use the cross!
I abjure thee,
oh creatures of salt
by the living God!
Mr. Russell!
Maitland!
Maitland! What's happened?
Uh, uh...
Pat! Patricia!
Hello,
Hello operator?!
Darn!
Pat!
We've been waiting for you.
Dick! These are the dead
who killed Nan!
Barlow.
Please help me!
Come on, Pat. Quick.
The only way!
Dick!
No!
Pat!
Dick!
Maitland!
Get to a cross. A cross!
The shadow of a cross!
Ugh!
Dick, Dick, he's moving!
Lift the cross!
Quick!
Witches of Salt, I abjure thee
by the living God.
Back from the cross!
Come nearer, Bill!
Get the shadow on them!
It comes nearer!
Do not fail!
We must finish the sacrifice.
- Dick!
- Pat!
Wait!
Wait for the hour of 13.
Pat, are you alright?!
I think so.
Bill!
We've got a score to settle
with Mrs. Newless!
You stay here.